James Handshoe

Student at Eleven Fifty Academy

handshoejames@gmail.com

Summary

I am a former head band director of 12 years transitioning into software development. During my time in education, I earned a Masters of Science in Educational Leadership and implemented project management processes into my classroom. Towards the end of my teaching career, I became interested in the world of computer programming and this curiosity led to me eventually leaving my teaching position to pursue new challenges in the software world.

My learning journey began by taking several courses in Python offered by Dr. Severance of University of Michigan on coursera.org. As a student in these classes I developed basic to intermediate coding skills. After these courses, I then purchased some classes on Udemy for Swift development. Soon after starting the Swift course, I decided to attend Eleven Fifty Academy in Carmel, IN to focus on JavaScript and web development. Through this opportunity, I have expanded my skills in the M.E.A.N. stack, jQuery, HTML and CSS.

I love learning and the new challenges presented in the web development world! I am excited to share my knowledge and experiences!

Experience

Student at Eleven Fifty Academy

2016 - Present (less than a year)

Eleven Fifty Academy, a nonprofit coding academy, strives to bring the most relevant coursework to the students. Students such as myself are continuously learning in an immersive environment and building our portfolios with the many programming instructors that work with us on a daily basis. We perfect our coding skills through different courses such as Agile, UI/UX, Testing, Deployment, the language courses and more. We're not only learning through coursework, but through projects and team exercises to challenge us every day. We learn how to code as well as how to work with our clients and how to properly present ourselves in the professional world.

Band Director at Frankton Jr. / Sr. High School

May 2008 - July 2016 (8 years 3 months)

Responsible for hiring and evaluating 3-5 staff members yearly

Supervised and coached two student teachers

Supervised and coached practicum students for Ball State University

Assisted in developing and implementing staff professional development

Designed and executed research on the flipped classroom teaching model

Developed and maintained budgets for the band program

Coordinated and organized logistics for several band and guard trips

Developed and maintained curriculum for the band and guard program

Assistant Band Director at South Side Middle School

2004 - 2008 (4 years)

Skills & Expertise

Teaching

Public Speaking

Leadership

Collaborative Leadership

Educational Leadership

Secondary Education

Bands

Staff Development

Strategic Planning

Classroom

Team Building

Lesson Planning

Curriculum Development

Customer Service

Microsoft Office

Microsoft Excel

Curriculum Design

Event Planning

Classroom Management

Social Media

Budgets

Educational Technology

K-12

Leadership Development

Teacher Training

Fundraising

Project Management

Management

Differentiated Instruction

Training

Research

Music

Instructional Design

Music Theory

Coaching

Instructional Technology

HTML

Node.js

HTML5

AngularJS

MongoDB

Github

Bootstrap

Education

Western Governors University

Master's Degree, Educational Leadership and Administration, General, 2011 - 2013

Anderson University

Bachelor's Degree, Music Teacher Education, 1999 - 2004

Eleven Fifty Academy

JavaScript, Web Development, 2016

Courses

Independent Coursework

Python Specialization Coursera

Understanding Research Methods Coursera

What's Your Big Idea Coursera

Creative Problem Sovling Coursera

Project Management: The Basics for Success

Coursera

Certifications

Gold Badge Coder

Eleven Fifty Academy July 2016

James Handshoe

Student at Eleven Fifty Academy

handshoejames@gmail.com



Contact James on LinkedIn